<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>
	<channel>
		<title>soafen's blog</title>
		<description>ramblings and updates from soafen herself</description>
		<link>http://soafen.love/blog</link>
		<category>Blog</category>
		<language>en-CA</language>
		<image>
			<url>http://soafen.love/img/cherryblossom.png</url>
			<title>soafen's blog</title>
			<link>http://soafen.love/blog</link>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>videos page updates</title>
			<category>site updates</category>
			<link>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/videos-page-updates</link>
			<guid>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/videos-page-updates</guid>
			<description>
				i know it's been a while since i posted here but here's an update!
			</description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://soafen.love/blog/2023/videos-page-updates/image1.jpg" width="650" height="488" alt="pictured: the old style of the videos page on the left, with an arrow pointing to the updated videos page on the right"/><p>i know it's been a while since i posted here but here's an update!</p><h3>goodbye, WMV !</h3><p>so i've uploaded my videos to YouTube, Odysee, Vanillo, PeerTube and BitView, along with a couple other places, but i've also been publishing 360p H264 videos right on this site, along with 240p 4:3 WMVs for maximum compatibility with older devices.</p><p>i've now realised, part of why i haven't been good with updating this website's copy of the videos is due to the time it takes to hand-edit and produce 4:3 edits for the WMV variants that realistically nobody will need, since you can decode H264 web video, especially standard-def 360p ones, on everything from a Wii U Browser to Windows 2000!</p><p>this also comes with the benefit of saving nearly 2GB of precious VPS storage space. i've used the extra space on the videos page to show the file size before you click to download.<br><h3>efficiency 100</h3><p>while H264 is an <i>old</i> codec and thus not the most efficient out there anymore, it also comes with the upside of the encoding side of things being very mature, making it possible to pretty easily squeeze out every bit of efficiency possible, which is worth it for the sheer compatbility of the codec in my opinion !</p><p>soo, while those versions of my videos won't look great on my 32-inch 4K monitor at my desk, for example, that's not what it's for. the 4K YouTube uploads (or better yet, the original, Source-quality renders on my <a href="//patreon.com/soafen">Patreon</a> or <a href="//ko-fi.com/soafen">Ko-fi</a> pages!) are for times where quality matters. having this option around, however, is pretty awesome as this allows you to watch soafen videos on places where even YouTube won't work anymore, 360p H264 video is pretty dang versatile!</p><br><p>be sure to send a tweet or write an e-mail showing soafen videos running on your weird devices, like a Blackberry Curve or the PS4's captive portal login browser, and maybe i'll feature some in my next blog post :3</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 03:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>hello world !</title>
			<category>site updates</category>
			<link>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/hello-world</link>
			<guid>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/hello-world</guid>
			<description>
			so, it's finally here, my very own blog, and it should be accessible all the way from the latest Android-powered kettle right down to the family DELL Dimension from the turn of the century, because why not?
			</description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>so, it's finally here, my very own blog, and it should be accessible all the way from the latest Android-powered kettle right down to the family DELL Dimension from the turn of the century, because why not?</p><h3>what took so long ?</h3><p>that is a gooood question. the answer is pretty straight forward: when i'm home, i'm busy with producing videos and streams! while i do get ideas for them all the time, side projects of mine such as the website and soafenTV are left to one side until i'm away from home, where i can't really work on videos or streams as much.</p><p>so now that i'm finally away from home, i got cracking on the final roadblock that was stopping this blog from existing–i do everything on this site by hand (...or paw), static site generators scare me, but i want to make my blog available over RSS!</p><p>as it turns out, RSS is pretty trivial to manually write by <s>hand</s> PAW!!1 and a <a href="//moth.monster/blog/rssbyhand/">guide that i came across</a> from moth.monster was a very helpful resource to get me going ^^</p><h3>what this blog is for</h3><p>i plan to use this blog to house two things:<ul><li>the first being general news and updates pertaining to myself and my site, and...</li><li>the second will likely be tutorials and guides for how to do things that maybe aren't easy to find or well documented, if at all!</li></ul></p><p>hopefully this will prove informative, helpful or at the very least interesting to someone else out there!</p><p>well that's pretty much all i have to share for now, i don't exactly have a comments section planned, but if you'd like to get in touch you may do so through <a href="//soafen.love/contact">my contact page</a>.</p><p>bye for now :3</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:47:00 UTC</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>