<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>
	<channel>
		<title>soafen's blog</title>
		<description>ramblings and updates from soafen herself</description>
		<link>http://soafen.love/blog</link>
		<category>Blog</category>
		<language>en-CA</language>
		<image>
			<url>http://soafen.love/img/cherryblossom.png</url>
			<title>soafen's blog</title>
			<link>http://soafen.love/blog</link>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>happy early new year !</title>
			<category>personal</category>
			<link>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/happy-early-new-year</link>
			<guid>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/happy-early-new-year</guid>
			<description>
				hai everyones, happy (early) new year !
			</description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>hai everyones, happy (early) new year !</p><p>indeed, the year has come to a close this fast and i'm already regretting not doing more with my blog, but the reality is that writing something that i feel is worth putting up here is a daunting task!</p><p>for one example, i've had the ambition to turn certain more informative videos into article-format for wider accessibility, like my video on <a href="https://vid.soafen.love/w/62gd2y5E3oTUfv3jZiBfyk">The Orange Box @ 60fps on Xbox 360</a>. i was planning on adapting the script i wrote (something i rarely do as i struggle with writing as mentioned before) for blog format and linking to it in the video description. i still plan on doing this as i think it would not only be helpful for those interested, but it could also raise awareness of the existence of this blog ^^</p><p>as for now though, i'm away from home visiting some people for the rest of the year, as a content creator the end of december is my only real break from things, so i need to make the most of the time i have. i've also been staying in practice with HTML + CSS by working on <a href="https://w2s.neocities.org">a new website for Workplace2Software</a> as i still do have ambitions to one day get into programming.</p><p>big thank-yous all around to everyone who stuck around or even dropped by this year, whether you were there for <a href="https://patreon.com/soafen">the opening of my Patreon</a>, the grand return of <a href="https://kick.com/soafenTV">soafenTV</a> or simply said "Hi" in our <a href="/discord">Discord server</a> or <a href="https://youtube.com/@soafen/live">stream chat</a>, thank you all. the community is why i do everything i do !</p><p>let me take a moment to highlight some of my personal achievements for this year:</p><ul><li>i completely remade my site with not just the appearance but the compatibiliy of browsers and devices from days of the early web, circa 1995-2005!</li><li>i joined <a href="https://vnlo.me/soafen">Vanillo</a> & <a href="https://bitview.net/user/soafen">BitView</a>, the communities on both have been very fun to join <3</li><li>i launched several new channels including soafenTF2 which has been quite fun for me; while i want to be careful not to spread myself too thin, it's been fun seeing what it would have looked like if i was a TF2ber</li><li>i moved my gaming PC to linux, Pop!_OS to be exact, that's one less Windows PC in this house >:3</li><li>as a direct result of the above, i've began to learn (and get pretty okay at) both Kdenlive and GIMP!</li><li>i put my previous negative experiences behind me and dove head-first into the world of self-hosting! i run things like Pi-Hole, Jellyfin and a TF2 server (was i the only one who didn't know TF2 in docker existed?!)</li><li>i launched, broke then launched again my very own PeerTube instance, <a href="https://vid.soafen.love">soafVid</a>!</li></ul><p>regarding plans for next year, then, there's a lot happening in 2024 and i need to be able to finally turn this into something i can do to support myself. i've always prioritised quality over quantity, sure, but i need to be able to deliver more consistently if i want a chance to be picked up by the algorithm gods. this means i'm going to not only have to get better at managing my time but also finding something that is both enjoyable for me (and thus results in engaging videos) and performs well!</p><p>i've been taking a look at the sorts of videos <i>i watch</i> these days as inspiration, and i've been realising that even someone such as myself who enjoys long stuff (if i like the creator, i'm talking looonngg! 40 minutes+!), even i don't really follow episodic gameplays. the only exception i can think of is certain games that come and go, that i would have loved to stream but missed my chance to. (Amanda the Adventurer, for instance)</p><p>all that to say, the days of episodic stuff like Stray, The Stanley Parable: Ultra Deluxe et cetera are behind us, instead i will be doing longer cuts of games for the channel as i see appropriate. they may contain segments from several streams if i feel the game only really needs one big video (if i was doing Stray now, it'd likely be just two long, cut up parts, and Stanley Parable: UD would be one).</p><p>a quick recap of the main things i do, as we did launch a lot of new stuff this year:</p><ul><li>i stream Mondays, Wednesdays, Fridays, the locations change fairly often but at time of writing i stream to <a href="https://youtube.com/@soafen/live">YouTube</a> & <a href="https://twitch.tv/imsoafen">Twitch</a> and am planning to either bring back my Owncast instance or get streaming to my PeerTube instance working reliably,</li><li>i run a (nearly!) 24-7 "TV channel" of sorts, at <a href="https://kick.com/soafenTV">soafenTV on Kick</a>,</li><li>i run the channels <strong>soafen</strong> (cut-down video game-related videos), <strong>soafen²</strong> (tech videos, tutorials, ramblings), <strong>soafen³</strong> (in limbo, i have plans though!), <strong>soafenMORE</strong> (some extra videos), <strong>soafenLIVE</strong>, a selection of some stream VODs, <strong>soafenCLIPS</strong>, 16:9 versions of some of my short-form content, <strong>soafenHEAVEN,</strong> a not-too-active music + ambiences collection, <strong>soafenTF2</strong>, a channel that answers the question nobody was asking: <i>"What if soafen was a TF2ber?</i>, <strong>soafen's recycle bin</strong>, a worrying amount of people asked for this one to be made, and there's a couple more in the works that i won't spoil for now :3</li><li>i run a group called <strong>Workplace2Software</strong> with my friends where we make satirical software and trailers for said software (that would make even Windows 93 blush!),</li><li>i dabble on rare occasion with music production and publish some of my creations on <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sophie-l-51583019">my SoundCloud</a>,</li><li>i provide several perks including early access occasional bonus videos on my <a href="https://patreon.com/soafen">Patreon</a> & <a href="https://ko-fi.com/soafen">Ko-fi</a> pages,</li><li>i <a href="/video-editing">edit videos for people on Fiverr</a>, a playlist is linked there with examples of my work</li></ul><p>that's all i can think to mention for now but i'm sure there's more! if i find any free time i'll maybe work on my websites or make something in <a href="https://scratch.mit.edu/users/soafen/">Scratch</a> or <a href="https://github.com/soafen">Visual Basic</a>, or perhaps work on a side channel with friends such as <a href="https://youtube.com/@WinstonBaits">The Winstons</a>, a group scambait channel, or dabble with server things. i'm a big self-hosting and distributed computing nerd, <a href="https://stats.foldingathome.org/donor/name/soafen">(here's my Folding@Home page!)</a> hell, i might even game! speaking of games...</p><p><i>do i use parentheses too often? (yes)</i></p><p>i've always wanted to have a place at the end of each year to acknowledge my favourites in certain categories, and, well, having the blog gives me a chance to do that! i'll keep it super brief:<ul><li>my favourite game i first played this year is <a href="http://www.towerunite.com/">Tower Unite (376 hours at time of writing)</a>,</li><li>my favourite album i first heard this year is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harmony_House_(Dayglow_album)">Dayglow's Harmony House (my frequently reset music player says it has 11 plays)</a>,</li><li>and finally my favourite YouTube creator i've discovered this year is <a href="https://youtube.com/@hbomberguy">hbomberguy (who i have watched three videos by thus far, rookie numbers i know)</a></li></ul>honourable mentions go to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2519830">Resonite</a>, <a href="https://donglekumquatarchive.com/">all of William Reid's music</a> & <a href="https://youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry">the amazing talent over at Digital Foundry</a>!</p><p>well i think that's all i have to say. if you've made it this far, wow, thanks for caring so much about what i have to say, and maybe there is some hope after all in this generation of <strike>Twitter</strike> X posts longer than 10 words being met with the instant reply of "i ain't readin allat"!</p><p>i hope you all have a happy and safe new year, and if there's one thing i'd like to leave you all with, something that i've learned this year, it's not to be overambitious - if you set huge dream goals that you'd love to reach, you may find yourself spending all your time fantasizing about getting there, but if you set yourself these smaller-chunked objectives, it can be really empowering and you may feel like you can do anything! it's certainly a lot more productive.</p><p>take this blog, for example. sure, i know how to do fancy effects, slick transitions and eye-catching animations, but i wanted something that would work on just about any browser. at the same time, i didn't want to go to the deep end of making sure when hand-writing this character-by-character i am adhering to every single HTML standard that ever existed, or that everything i'm doing works 100% on everything ever. i've struck a balance early on that i was happy with, and as a result i could spend a lot more time expanding the contents of this new site, and making little additions and changes as the year went on until today where i'm left with something i'm really happy with!</p><p>i hope you people crush your goals for 2024, or if you don't have any (whether you can't think of some or don't want to), just remember that you're still you, we're still here, and that's the important part! whatever hardships you may be going through now can and will be overcome with enough determination. i believe in you ! <3</p><p>i'll see you all next year, bye for now and thank you all for your support !</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 15:45:00 UTC</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>videos page updates</title>
			<category>site updates</category>
			<link>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/videos-page-updates</link>
			<guid>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/videos-page-updates</guid>
			<description>
				i know it's been a while since i posted here but here's an update!
			</description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://soafen.love/blog/2023/videos-page-updates/image1.jpg" width="650" height="488" alt="pictured: the old style of the videos page on the left, with an arrow pointing to the updated videos page on the right"/><p>i know it's been a while since i posted here but here's an update!</p><h3>goodbye, WMV !</h3><p>so i've uploaded my videos to YouTube, Odysee, Vanillo, PeerTube and BitView, along with a couple other places, but i've also been publishing 360p H264 videos right on this site, along with 240p 4:3 WMVs for maximum compatibility with older devices.</p><p>i've now realised, part of why i haven't been good with updating this website's copy of the videos is due to the time it takes to hand-edit and produce 4:3 edits for the WMV variants that realistically nobody will need, since you can decode H264 web video, especially standard-def 360p ones, on everything from a Wii U Browser to Windows 2000!</p><p>this also comes with the benefit of saving nearly 2GB of precious VPS storage space. i've used the extra space on the videos page to show the file size before you click to download.<br><h3>efficiency 100</h3><p>while H264 is an <i>old</i> codec and thus not the most efficient out there anymore, it also comes with the upside of the encoding side of things being very mature, making it possible to pretty easily squeeze out every bit of efficiency possible, which is worth it for the sheer compatbility of the codec in my opinion !</p><p>soo, while those versions of my videos won't look great on my 32-inch 4K monitor at my desk, for example, that's not what it's for. the 4K YouTube uploads (or better yet, the original, Source-quality renders on my <a href="//patreon.com/soafen">Patreon</a> or <a href="//ko-fi.com/soafen">Ko-fi</a> pages!) are for times where quality matters. having this option around, however, is pretty awesome as this allows you to watch soafen videos on places where even YouTube won't work anymore, 360p H264 video is pretty dang versatile!</p><br><p>be sure to send a tweet or write an e-mail showing soafen videos running on your weird devices, like a Blackberry Curve or the PS4's captive portal login browser, and maybe i'll feature some in my next blog post :3</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 03:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>hello world !</title>
			<category>site updates</category>
			<link>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/hello-world</link>
			<guid>http://soafen.love/blog/2023/hello-world</guid>
			<description>
			so, it's finally here, my very own blog, and it should be accessible all the way from the latest Android-powered kettle right down to the family DELL Dimension from the turn of the century, because why not?
			</description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>so, it's finally here, my very own blog, and it should be accessible all the way from the latest Android-powered kettle right down to the family DELL Dimension from the turn of the century, because why not?</p><h3>what took so long ?</h3><p>that is a gooood question. the answer is pretty straight forward: when i'm home, i'm busy with producing videos and streams! while i do get ideas for them all the time, side projects of mine such as the website and soafenTV are left to one side until i'm away from home, where i can't really work on videos or streams as much.</p><p>so now that i'm finally away from home, i got cracking on the final roadblock that was stopping this blog from existing–i do everything on this site by hand (...or paw), static site generators scare me, but i want to make my blog available over RSS!</p><p>as it turns out, RSS is pretty trivial to manually write by <s>hand</s> PAW!!1 and a <a href="//moth.monster/blog/rssbyhand/">guide that i came across</a> from moth.monster was a very helpful resource to get me going ^^</p><h3>what this blog is for</h3><p>i plan to use this blog to house two things:<ul><li>the first being general news and updates pertaining to myself and my site, and...</li><li>the second will likely be tutorials and guides for how to do things that maybe aren't easy to find or well documented, if at all!</li></ul></p><p>hopefully this will prove informative, helpful or at the very least interesting to someone else out there!</p><p>well that's pretty much all i have to share for now, i don't exactly have a comments section planned, but if you'd like to get in touch you may do so through <a href="//soafen.love/contact">my contact page</a>.</p><p>bye for now :3</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:47:00 UTC</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>